<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portfolio</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet My Dog Zeke!</title>
      <link>/blog/meet-my-dog-zeke/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/meet-my-dog-zeke/</guid>
      <description>Everyone meet Zeke, my 2 year old fox red laborador. Yes, he has oddly beautiful human eyes and a pink nose, unlike most laboradors. Being curious traits for a labrodor of his type, I had to do some research. Turns out, my son is a rare type of lab called a Dudley. The Dudley trait, most common to laborodors, is essentially albinism for dogs in which they do not have pigment in their nose and their eyes tend to be a yellow or greenish hue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R and Python Can Communicate</title>
      <link>/blog/r-and-python-can-communicate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/r-and-python-can-communicate/</guid>
      <description>Imagine you are sitting at your desk working through R studio and your mind begins wandering away. You start to think about what life would be like out of school, and begin to fantasize over your hopes and dreams. The nerd in me, however, begins to think about how R and Python can communicate with each other and how I could make that work.
Well, I am in luck because if you go online and listen to your professor who knows a lot (at least mine does), you’ll come to realize that this isn’t a very difficult task.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Here are some projects I have recently completed:
  Exploratory Data Analysis with Tidyverse Tools
  Modeling, Testing, and Classification
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1: Exploratory Data Analysis</title>
      <link>/project1-og/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project1-og/</guid>
      <description>library(readxl) library(knitr) library(dplyr) library(tidyverse) library(ggplot2) library(stringr) library(fivethirtyeight) states &amp;lt;- state_info scores &amp;lt;- read_excel(&amp;quot;Statesinfo.xlsx&amp;quot;) # ?state_info The two datasets I have chosen share a common variable ‘state’. One of the datasets came from the fivethirteight package called ‘state_info’, and the other came from the carData package laebled ‘States’. The first dataset gives all 51 US states and includes 4 categorical varibales as follows: the state name (state), state abbreviation (state_abbrev), US census designated division (division), and the US census designated region (region).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2: Modeling, Testing, and Predicting</title>
      <link>/project2-og/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project2-og/</guid>
      <description>library(LearnBayes) head(studentdata) ## Student Height Gender Shoes Number Dvds ToSleep WakeUp Haircut Job Drink ## 1 1 67 female 10 5 10 -2.5 5.5 60 30.0 water ## 2 2 64 female 20 7 5 1.5 8.0 0 20.0 pop ## 3 3 61 female 12 2 6 -1.5 7.5 48 0.0 milk ## 4 4 61 female 3 6 40 2.0 8.5 10 0.0 water ## 5 5 70 male 4 5 6 0.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>